Finding Aid for David M. Dennison papers, 1884-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
David M. Dennison papers 1884-1989 1926-1976
Dennison, David M.
85132 Aa 2
Papers of David M. Dennison, professor of physics at the University of Michigan; contain lecture notes and exam materials, correspondence, speeches, files relating to research in theoretical physics, University of Michigan and travel files.
8 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated in multiple installments by Mrs. Helen Dennison (donor no. 5254 ) between 1972 and 1981 and by Sam Dennison (donor no. 10967 ) in July 2013.
The collection is open to research.
David Mathias Dennison was born in Oberlin, Ohio, in 1900 to Walter Dennison and Anna L. Green. He attended Swarthmore College and graduated with a BA in 1921 before starting graduate work at the University of Michigan. In 1924 Dennison received his Ph. D. from Michigan, married his wife Helen Lenette Johnson, and began a three-year study of physics in Europe. While studying at Cambridge, Dennison began theoretical work on the heat and temperature of hydrogen with his experiments yielding some of the first quantitative evidence for nuclear spin.
After returning to the United States in 1927 Dennison joined the University of Michigan’s Physics Department as part of a number of new hires with a background in theoretical physics; he was made a full professor in 1935. While working at Michigan, Dennison began to diversify his interest in physics making important discoveries about microwave spectroscopy, and the stability of particle orbits in the racetrack synchrotron. His work on the performance of the radio proximity fuse during World War II earned him a Certificate for Exceptional Service from the United States Navy. In addition Dennison helped organize and participated in international symposia of physicists held during the summer at the University of Michigan from 1929 to 1940.
During his 44 years at the University of Michigan Dennison earned many honors. In 1952 he was selected as the Henry Russel Lecturer, a high honor bestowed on senior faculty, he received a distinguished faculty award in 1962, and was appointed the Harrison M. Randall Distinguished Faculty Professor in 1966. Dennison retired in 1971. His important contributions to science and his dedication to the University of Michigan lead to the renaming of the Physics-Astronomy Building on the university campus to the David M. Dennison Building following his death in 1976.
The David M. Dennison Papers contain both the personal correspondence of the Dennison family and items relating to David M. Dennison's research and teaching while at the University of Michigan.
The first part of the collection is correspondence from 1894-1896 from James Lutheran Dennison and his wife to their son Walter Dennison, the father of David M. Dennison. One folder contains correspondence from George Dennison and his wife Nina to his brother Walter Dennison also from the 1890s.
Biographical and personal materials for David M Dennison are comprised of letters from David M. Dennison and his wife, Helen Lenette Johnson, memorial materials from David's death, home finances, and travel information. Family documents in this collection are comprised mostly of his son Edwin's Ph.D. research at the University of Michigan. Dennison's papers include various speeches, articles, and other writings about the physics he was studying, primarily focused on the later part of Dennison's time at the University. Materials from the University of Michigan include lecture notes and exams from the many physics classes Dennison taught. Documents relating to administration of the physics department and David's colleagues are also a part of this collection. Of note is David and Helen's correspondence and connection to the Niels Bohr Institute.
Audio-visual materials in the collection include photographs of David and Helen from the early 1900s through the 1970s. There are also two cassette tapes with recording of talks given by David, as well as photograph negatives and spectroscopic plates, lantern slides depicting astronomical images pertaining to his astro-physics research.
Subjects:
Dennison, David M. (David Mathias), 1900-1976.; Dennison, Edwin W.; Dennison, Helen.; University of Michigan. Department of Physics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Students.; Physics.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bohr, Niels, 1885-1962.; Denmark.; Dennison, David M. (David Mathias), 1900-1976.; Dennison, Walter, 1869-1917.; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Dennison, David M. (David Mathias), 1900-1976.; Physics.; Proximity fuzes.; Audiocassettes.; Sound recordings.
Contributors:
Baldwin, Ralph Belknap, 1912-
Genre Terms:
Lantern slides.; Negatives (photographic); Photographs.; Stereoscopic photographs.; Classrooms--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- James Lutheran Dennison and his wife
  - Correspondence
    - August-December 1894 (Box 1)
    - January-February 1895 (Box 1)
    - March .-May 1895 (Box 1)
    - June-September 1895 (Box 1)
    - October-December 1895 (Box 1)
    - January-March 1896 (Box 1)
    - April-December 1896 (Box 1)
    - 1897-1914 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
- George Dennison and his wife Nina (son and daughter-in-law of James Lutheran Dennison)
  - Correspondence 1894-1895 (Box 1)
- David Mathias Dennison (1900-1976), son of Walter Dennison
  - Biographical and personal
    - Correspondence (including letters of David's wife Helen Johnson Dennison 1924-1927 written from Europe)
      - Undated (Box 1)
      - January-September 1924 (Box 1)
      - October-December 1924 (Box 1)
      - January-March 1925 (Box 1)
      - April-June 1925 (Box 1)
      - July-September 1925 (Box 1)
      - October-December 1925 (Box 1)
      - January-March 1926 (Box 1)
      - April-June 1926 (Box 1)
      - July-September 1926 (Box 1)
      - October-December 1926 (Box 1)
      - January-March 1927 (Box 1)
      - April-June 1927 (Box 1)
      - July-September 1927 (Box 1)
      - October-December 1927 (Box 1)
      - 1930-1931, 1935-1939 (Box 1)
      - 1940-1943 (Box 1)
      - January-June 1944 (Box 1)
      - July-December 1944 (Box 1)
      - January-March 1945 (Box 1)
      - April-December 1945 (Box 1)
      - 1946-1948 (Box 1)
      - 1950-1951, 1954-1955, 1957 (Box 1)
      - 1958 (Box 1)
      - 1959 (Box 1)
      - 1960 (Box 1)
      - 1961 (Box 1)
      - 1962 (Box 1)
      - 1963 (Box 1)
      - 1964 (Box 1)
      - 1965 (Box 1)
      - 1966 (Box 1)
      - 1967 (Box 1)
      - 1968 (Box 1)
      - 1969 (Box 1)
      - 1970 (Box 1)
      - 1971 (Box 1)
      - 1972 (Box 1)
      - 1973 (Box 1)
      - 1974 (Box 1)
      - 1975, 1981 to Helen Dennison (Box 1)
      - Condolence letters 1976, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Dr. Esther Boise Van Deman (Box 1)
      - Lady Sutherland to Helen 1964-1981 (Box 6)
        (Lady Sutherland's husband was a physics professor who taught at the University of Michigan)
      - Retirement dinner 1969 (Box 6)
      - Universities 1927-1976 (Box 6)
    - Hawthorn House 1954-1955 (Box 6)
    - Honors 1945-1970 (Box 6)
    - In Memoriam 1976-1979 (Box 6)
    - Memoirs and Obituaries 1976 (Box 6)
    - National Academy of Sciences 1963-1966 (Box 6)
    - Township Taxes 1920-1981 (Box 6)
    - Travel
      - 1961-1963 (Box 6)
      - 1975 (Box 6)
      - Passports 1924-1979 (Box 6)
  - Family
    - Edwin W. Dennison
      (one of David's sons)
      - Correspondence 1953-1954 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous 1940-1951 (Box 6)
      - Notes and writings 1951 (Box 6)
      - University of Michigan
        - Astronomy Class 1953 (Box 6)
        - Dissertation 1954 (Box 7)
        - Dissertation research-Curtis Telescope 1954 (Box 7)
          (includes spectroscopic plates)
        - Research, 1954(?), 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Helen Dennison 1975-1989 (Box 7)
  - Speeches and writings
    - 1920s, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 1930s (Box 7)
    - 1940s (Box 7)
    - 1950s (Box 7)
    - 1960s (Box 7)
    - 1970s (Box 7)
    - Concepts of Physics-Science Club (Box 2)
    - Early Development of Molecular Theory (Box 2)
    - Gas Phase Molecular Conference-Banquet Speech (Box 2)
    - Gravitation Talk (Box 2)
    - Intensities of Lines (Box 2)
    - Manuscripts, 1965(?) (Box 7)
    - Methonal Talk December 1, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Molecular Spectroscopy Bohr Conference July 8-15, 1963, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Molecular Spectroscopy Symposium (Box 2)
    - Normal Coordinates Talk-the Gordon Conference (Box 2)
    - Physics and Physicists 1974 (Box 7)
      (includes photographs)
    - Physics Since 1900 and the Department of Physics at the University of Michigan (Box 2)
    - Proton Spin and specific heat of Hydrogen (Box 2)
    - "Recollections of Physics and of Physicists during the 1920s" (Box 2)
    - Something About Molecules (Box 2)
    - Survey of the Spectrum of Water Vapor (Box 2)
    - Symposium in Theoretical Physics (Box 2)
    - William Thomson-Lord Kelvin Speech to the Research Club Council (Box 2)
    - Time Speech (Box 2)
    - Interviews
      - Interviews, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Zorn and Conzett 1964 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Selection of Biophysics Director for Institute of Science and Technology (Box 2)
    - Colleagues 1956-1978 (Box 7)
      (includes a photograph)
    - Committee on the Deanship of L.S.A. (Box 2)
    - Dennison articles on Randall and Laporte 1970-1971 (Box 7)
    - Dennison Building 1963-1976 (Box 7)
    - Department administration 1955-1959 (Box 7)
    - News articles and meetings 1926-1974, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Notes undated (Box 7)
    - Physics Department Report 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - President's Club 1971-1977 (Box 7)
    - Prof. H. Richard Crane and Prof. Otto Laporte (Box 2)
    - Prof. Harrison Randall (Box 2)
      - Biographical (Box 2)
      - American Institute of Physics interview (Box 2)
    - Research Illustrations undated (Box 7)
    - Salary 1927-1969 (Box 7)
    - University of Michigan Physics Ph.D. Graduates list (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Topical file
    - Attempts to calculate the change in Barrier Height (Box 2)
    - Bohr Institute 1927-1981, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - CH3DH Manuscript (Box 2)
    - Colloquium at Tours September 1975 (Box 8)
    - The Dark Ground Calculation papers (Box 2)
    - Section of Methyl Alcohol in the Orion Nebula (Box 2)
    - Energy Levels of the 016 Nucleus (Box 2)
    - Group Theory (Box 2)
    - History of Physics (Box 2)
    - Infrared Measurements (Box 2)
    - Infra Red Rotation Spectrum of Methyl Alcohol (Box 2)
    - Magnetic Field Trap (Box 2)
    - Methanol Research (Box 2)
    - National Academy of Sciences review of the University of Colorado Report on UFOs., 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Polarization of White Dwarfs (Box 2)
    - Sensitive Plant and Pendulum, circa 1972 (Box 8)
    - Synchrotron papers (Box 3)
    - V6 Redundancy Relation (Box 3)
  - Class Lecture Notes and Exams
    - Physics 198, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Quantum Theory no. 1, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Quantum Theory no. 1 Cold], 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Quantum Theory no. 2, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Quantum Theory no. 2 Cold], 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Mechanics, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Mechanics 1, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Mechanics 11, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Mechanics 111, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Mechanics Exams and Problems, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Statistical Mechanics, 7 folders (Box 4)
    - Statistics, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Thermodynamics, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Thermodynamics Problems and Exams (Box 4)
    - Bond Spectra, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Student Evaluation of Dennison's Physics 506 (Box 4)
    - Introduction to Electricity and Magnetism, 8 folders (Box 4)
    - Introduction to Electricity and Magnetism-Problems, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Electricity and Magnetism no. 1, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Electricity and Magnetism no. 1 Problems, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Electricity and Magnetism no. 1 [old], 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Electricity and Magnetism no. 2, 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Electricity and Magnetism no. 2 Problems, 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Electricity and Magnetism no. 2 Cold3, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Problems in Electricity and Magnetism (Box 5)
  - Audio and visual materials
    - Dennison talks Cassette tapes, 2 tapes (Box 8)
      ((1)Trial run of talk for the Physical Society in Chicago, February 6, 1974 and (2)Ralph Baldwin, Dick [...], and David Dennison talk about The Early Days of the Proximity Fuze, undated)
    - Early photographs 1908-1931 (Box 8)
    - 1950s photographs (Box 8)
    - 1960s photographs (Box 8)
    - 1970s photographs (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous photographs undated (Box 8)
    - Symposium photographs 1928-1941 (Box 8)
    - Television talks and brunch 1949, 1950, 1953 (Box 8)
      (Television talks from 1949 and 1953 other photographs from Brunch in 1950)
    - Slides, plates, and negatives 1952-1955 (Box 8)
      (includes spectroscopic plates, lantern slides, and photograph negatives)
  - Miscellaneous research notes, 10 folders (Box 5)
Selective Index to Correspondents
[This index was prepared by a researcher.]
Academic Press Inc.
April 2, 1968; April 18, 1966; May 27, 1966; June 17, 1966; Oct. 27, 1960; Nov. 10, 1959; July 12, 1957; Aug.1957; Oct. 9, 1957
Charles Ahonen
Jan. 12, 1959
S.L. Altmann
July 21, 1957
Ralph B. Baldwin
Aug. 18, 1975; Oct. 15, 1975
Stanley S. Ballard
March 9, 1970
E.F. Barker
Aug. 3, 1951; March 15, 1948
Paul F. Bartunek
. Jan. 22, 1959
P.R. Bates
June 15, 1959; Feb 4, 1958; June 18, 1957; July 2, 1957
Toni Becker
Feb 9, 1973
Willard H. Bennett
March 28, 1958
David G. Black, Jr.
Jan. 6, 1971
Allen E. Blaurock
July 22, 1970
The Boeing Company
Dec. 7, 1961
James E. Boggs
Sept. 16, 1975
Aage Bohr
1981
N. Bohr
June 9, 1927
Wesley E Brittin
March 1, 1955; May 15, 1958
R.J. Burke
April 18, 1958
Donald J. Burkhard
Sept. 30, 1958; Oct. 9, 1958
Gordon Burwash
Dec. 18, 1967
Leroy Cabbage
Jan. 28, 1958
David C. Carey
Nov. 25, 1974
CERN: European Org. for Nuclear Research
Jan. 5, 1962; May 4, 1961; Aug. 5, 1960
Bertrand Tsu-Shen Chang
Nov. 11, 1970; April 3, 1969; April 16, 1969; Dec. 3, 1968; Feb 1, 1967; March 2, 1967; Dec. 5, 1966; March 14, 1965; Dec. 23, 1965
Chrysler Corporation
May 1, 1962; Feb 10, 1961; Nov. 30, 1961; Jan. 25, 1960; May 10, 1960; Dec. 22, 1959
W. Preston Corderman
March 1, 1955
C.C. Costain
June6, 1967
C.A. Coulson, F.R.S.
Oct. 18, 1957; Sept. 17, 1957
Edward E. David, Jr.
May 16, 1972
William L. Dawson
Feb 20, 1958
Stanley Deser
Dec. 16, 1963
Dow Chemical Co.
May 19, 1969
Jesse W.M. Du Mond
Sept. 13, 1965
V.A. Edgeloe
Aug. 27, 1970
Steve Edwards
Sept. 18, 1975
P. Ehrenfest
May 30, 1927
William Ellis
April 29, 1963
K.G. Emeleus
Feb 8, 1966
D.S. Fahrney
Oct. 24, 1972
C.B. Farmer
Dec. 20, 1971
G. W. Ford
April 21, 1964
R. H. Fowler
Sept. 12, 1926; undated
Richard G. Fowler
June 9, 1970
William A. Fowler
April 10, 1967; July 5, 1967; Sept. 22, 1967; Nov. 17, 1966
Thomas Francis, Jr. M.D.
Feb 20, 1967; Sept. 28, 1967
Marchion R. Fugill
April 13, 1967
John S. Garing
Sept. 21, 1971
Dr. H.A. Gebbie
Aug. 19, 1970; Aug. 1, 1962
Gordon (lst name only)
Nov. 13, 1954
Gordon Research Conferences
Aug. 27, 1962
Samuel A. Goudsmit
Sept. 15, 1971; Sept. 23, 1958
Walter Goxly
May 27, 1962
Wayne Gruner
Feb 4, 1963
Prof. Dr. H. H. Günthard
Oct. 12, 1970
William Haber
Aug. 18, 1964
Marchy D. Hanf
April 11, 1960
Harold P. Hanson
Oct. 3, 1967
Mrs. B.E. Harrell
Jan. 9, 1963
Marchk A. Heald
May 16, 1968
Per Chr. Hemmer
Jan. 3, 1975
Algo D. Henderson
Jan. 20, 1964
G. Herzberd
Feb 5, 1975
Ralph E. Hiatt
Nov. 18, 1968
A.B. Hicks
March 8, 1965
Richard Hildebrand
Sept. 21, 1971
R. Hofstadter
Feb 7, 1963
John N. Howard
Sept. 21, 1971
F. Hoyle
Oct. 9, 1967
Bob Hunt
Oct. 9, 1972; Dec. 10, 1970
Indian Institute of Tech.
Ma- 24 1960
Hubert M. James
Sept. 11, 1973
Walter J. Johnson
July 12, 1957
Charles W. Joiner
Oct. 28, 1963
Lawrence W. Jones
Feb 17, 1964
E. Leonard Jossem.
April 22, 1971
Journal of Molecular Spectroscopy
Feb 16, 1963; Nov. 23, 1954
Journal of Polymer Science
April 5, 1960; April 13, 1960
Hyun Chai Juneg
Nov. 8, 1972
David Kinley
Jan. 27, 1930
Oscar Koon
Jan. 11, 1927; Jan. 22, 1927
J.V. Kotwal
Nov. 11, 1971
Thomas S. Kuhn
Jan. 15, 1964; Feb 25, 1964; Aug. 3, 1964
W. Kuhn
June 10, 1926
P. Kush
Sept. 18, 1972
Yuen Yuen Kwan
Nov. 11, 1975; Jan. 26, 1974; Dec. 15, 1974; Feb 17, 1972; May 2, 1972; Sept. 19, 1972; Oct. 16, 1972; Dec. 20, 1971
Robert Lagemann
April 1, 1958
Otto Laporte
Nov. 1, 1961; Jan. 4, 1954
Bertel Laurent
Dec. 16, 1963
G.L. Lee, Jr.
May 29, 1958
R.M. Lees
Jan. 27, 1972; March 2, 1972; Dec. 21, 1972; Aug. 19, 1971; Dec. 15, 1971; Jan. 22, 1969
W.K. Li
Feb 27, 1975
Naomi F. Liggett for Dr. Anderson
Aug. 17, 1966
J.W. Linnett
Feb 24, 1972; Oct. 3, 1966
M.A.K. Lodhi
Nov. 15, 1972
R.A. McClatchey
Sept. 21, 1971
Marchvin W. McFarland
April 9, 1973
Dean E. McHenry
Aug. 14, 1964
Pat McNamara
March 12, 1958
L.A. Matheson
Sept. 10, 1970; May 28, 1969
George Meader
March 13, 1958
Charles F. Meyer
March 29, 1958
F.C. Michelsen
Nov. 12, 1963
Freeman D. Miller
March 15, 1968
John A. Miller
March 15, 1926
K.D. Moeller
Feb 12, 1968
R.S. Mulliken
March 27, 1958
John Brent Musgrave
March 18, 1975
Takao Nagamiya
June 15, 1958; Oct. 15, 1958
National Academy of Sciences National Research Council
Jan. 6, 1966; Jan. 20, 1966; Feb 15, 1966
National Academy of Sciences
March 8, 1963
National Science Foundation
Feb 8, 1962; June 13, 1962; June 30, 1962; July 16, 1962; Nov. 19, 1962; Nov. 21, 1962; Nov. 27, 1962
National Symposium on Molecular Structure & Spectroscopy
May 10, 1962; July 9, 1962
D.L. Navasimham.
Oct. 15, 1968
Marvin L. Niehuss
Feb 14, 1958
Alvin H. Nielsen
March 28, 1958
Harald H. Nielsen
March 19, 1963; April 1, 1958
Journal of Molecular Spectroscopy (Harald H. Nielsen)
Sept. 23, 1960; May 26, 1960; May 27, 1960
Charles E. Odegaard
June 19, 1958; Aug. 19, 1957; Oct. 14, 1957
W.H. Parkinson
June 15, 1971
W. George Parks
July 13, 1960
John A. Perkins
June 10, 1958
Martin Perl
Nov. 6, 1962
Frederick M. Phelps III
Dec. 24, 1972
Earle K. Plyler
March 20, 1969
Charles E. Potter
March 10, 1958
Prentice Hall Inc.
April 22, 1963
Eleanor G. Price
Aug. 21, 197.0
Derek J. Prowse
June 24, 1970
D.A. Ramsey
Aug. 9, 1974; Oct. 15, 1974; May 6, 1960
H. M. Randall
May 5, 1926; Jan. 14, 1927; Feb 20, 1940; April 18, 1940; Nov. 1, 1939; Dec. 14, 1939; Aug. 31, 1937; Jan. 29, 1936; Aug. 7, 1935; June 3, 1931; Aug. 7, 1930
K. Narahari Rao
Feb 19, 1975; May 1, 1975
Frank H.T. Rhodes
Jan. 4, 1973
L. Rosenfeld
May 6, 1963; Aug. 28, 1962
Ernest D. Riggsby
[no date provided]
F .Rohrlich
March 16, 1966
L. Rosenfeld
[no date provided]
Royal Globe Insurance Co.
April 5, 1963
Prof. H. Salie
June 9, 1971
Ralph Sawyer
Dec. 5, 1962; Dec. 23, 1946
Maarten Schmidt
April 12, 1967
R.S. Shanbland
Dec. 17, 1974
Beatrice Shube
April 28, 1971; Sept. 15, 1971
Robert L. Simmons, J
Jan. 20, 1971
Zaka I. Slawsky
April 8, 1958
Marland B. Small
May 29, 1946
Allan F. Smith
June 20, 1969
Hilton A. Smith
Nov. 6, 1974
Katherine J. Sopka
April 5, 1972; May 24, 1972; Oct. 2, 1973
James B. Stamatoff
Feb 23, 1971
John Strong
Aug. 8, 1960
P.A. Sturrock
Nov. 27, 1974
Gorden Sutherland
May 25, 1963; June 2, 1963
Edwin F. Taylor
Feb 12, 1974
Donald F. Thackrey
June 14, 1966
Merle A. Tuve
Oct. 2, 1967; Nov. 14, 1967; July 7, 1966
George Uhlenbeck
Aug. 31, 1970
University of Madras, India
Nov. 15, 1960
University of Michigan
Aug. 20, 1962
U.S. Dept. of Commerce Nat. Bureau of Standards
Jan. 21, 1960
David B. van Hulsteyn
Jan. 8, 1968
J.H. Van Vleck
April 4, 1974; June 6, 1972; Feb 20, 1967; Feb 28, 1967; Oct. 23, 1967; Dec. 7, 1967
T. Venkatarayuda
July 10, 1974
Erich A. Walter
June 22, 1964
Joan Nelson Warnow
Jan. 22, 1968
Herbert T. Watkins
April 3, 1939; May 1, 1939; Dec. 16, 1930
A.B. Weaver
March 10, 1958
Ernest Weber
Oct. 27, 1967
H.A. Weidenmüller
Dr. D.A. Wells
Oct. 8, 1971
H. L. Welsh
Oct. 29, 1974
George L. West
Jan. 22, 1962
Stuart E. Whitcomb
April 1, 1958
G. Mennen Williams
Dec. 5, 1957
E. Bright Wilson
April 10, 1958
M. Kent Wilson
April 11, 1960
Louise Gray Young
Feb 2, 1972; Nov. 99 1971